<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Sitefig blog</title>
  <subtitle>Your site sorted</subtitle>
  <link href="https://sitefig.net/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://sitefig.net"/>
  <updated>2022-10-08T07:41:34.000+02:00</updated>
  <id>https://sitefig.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Len Dierickx</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Release v1.1.0</title>
    <link href="https://sitefig.net/release-v1-1-0/"/>
    <updated>2022-10-08T07:41:34.000+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://sitefig.net/release-v1-1-0/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We received several customer comments, and release v1.1 is the first update with changes reflecting those requests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The update focuses on software architecture, performance, bug fixes and two new report pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;software-architecture&quot;&gt;Software architecture&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sitefig architecture was built with live updates, allowing 98% uptime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At least that is the idea, but we never had a chance to test it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously we did a lot of updates, which meant downtime, even during the week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The previously announced update went well and without any downtime. So we are now confident that we can update the application without interrupting the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many pages did not perform very well, and we believe there is still much room for improvement. At least, that is what the Sitefig report is telling us!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, we used Sitefig on our application to figure out what needed updating. Which network requests were lagging, and which metric was the worst one?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TTF (Time to first byte) was the worst metric due to heavy queries and inlined images. The updates in this release reduced the TTF by 75%, which made using the application feel much more fluid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;report-pages&quot;&gt;Report pages&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two new report pages were made available to the customer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;-Javascript libraries and vulnerabilities,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;– and PDF assets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;javascript-libraries-and-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;Javascript libraries and vulnerabilities&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 60% of the websites scanned by Sitefig have at least one library with a known vulnerability. The percentage found at Sitefig is much higher than the result Snyk found when scanning popular websites, which was 37%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most common library loaded is still jQuery, even in 2022. And most of those jQuery versions are pretty old. They have not been forgotten due to legacy functionality packed with WordPress plugins or because it was bundled in a more extensive library and never updated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;pdf-assets&quot;&gt;PDF Assets&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously Sitefig did not load any PDf documents and focused only on HTML results. This has changed, and PDF documents are now also loaded and listed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-next&quot;&gt;What is next?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We plan to review some of the reports in the next release and update the UI to match a new plan for Sitefig.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following features will be coming as well:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ticketing integration (Jira, Bugzilla, and … )&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Accessibility audits for PDF documents&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Screenshots for different sizes and devices&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking about a feature, need anything specific, drop a comment, and we will contact you to see if we can offer a solution&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why you need HTTPS</title>
    <link href="https://sitefig.net/why-you-need-https/"/>
    <updated>2022-10-08T07:40:19.000+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://sitefig.net/why-you-need-https/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;everything-you-need-to-know-about-securing-your-website&quot;&gt;Everything you need to know about securing your website.&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;All websites these days should use HTTPS (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure).&lt;br /&gt;Yes, there was a time TLS (Transport Layer Security) certificates were unnecessary, but today you really cannot go without them. Here is why!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_Transfer_Protocol_Secure&quot;&gt;HTTPS&lt;/a&gt; is the encrypted version of HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol), the protocol used for transferring data to your browsers. The HTTPS protocol relies on a TLS certificate to encrypt all the data between your computer and the server. As a result, HTTPS prevents anyone from tampering with the data and ensures content integrity, and it works both ways: when receiving and sending data such as usernames, passwords and visa card numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The benefits of having a secured website far outweigh the downsides, which range from personal data loss, website impersonation attacks and lawsuits brought to you by any DPA (Data Protection Authority) in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, in 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://edpb.europa.eu/news/national-news/2021/dutch-dpa-orthodontic-practice-fined-unsecured-patient-website_en&quot;&gt;the Dutch DPA imposed a €12,000 fine&lt;/a&gt; on an orthodontic practice for allowing new patients to register on an unsecured website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can obtain TLS certificates for free, which means paying that hefty price was unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-benefits-of-a-secure-website&quot;&gt;The benefits of a secure website&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With HTTPS, intruders can’t manipulate or passively listen in on the communications between your site and your users. An HTTPS connection provides additional security and privacy for your company and customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The encryption makes it practically impossible to eavesdrop or snoop on any communication. While your customers are online, browsing or entering sensitive data on your website, nobody will be able to track what they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the company operating the website can be sure that no 3rd party is making changes to the website and the customer effectively sees the website as expected. You might be surprised how many companies have injected marketing messages, advertising, script and images onto pages browsed on open WiFi networks. It happened pretty often.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Luckily the need for privacy increased, and TLS certificates became much more common. Most of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.builtwith.com/ssl&quot;&gt;websites in the top 1 million are now using HTTPS &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The certificate is also a means of authentication and proves that your user sees and uses the intended website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/sitefig.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image.png?resize=560%2C212&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Certificate for the google.com website&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;212&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Certificate for the google.com website.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;privacy-and-trust&quot;&gt;Privacy and trust&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides security for your company and your customer, privacy concerns have become the focal point of several new directives and legislation efforts worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We already mentioned the need to use HTTP to avoid anyone snooping n the communication between your website and the customers’ browser. Here is why that is important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2021 &lt;a href=&quot;https://edpb.europa.eu/news/national-news/2021/dutch-dpa-orthodontic-practice-fined-unsecured-patient-website_en&quot;&gt;a complaint was lodged to the Dutch DPA&lt;/a&gt; about the website of an orthodontic practice. The registration forms on the website in question asked for all kinds of personal data about the patient’s health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the form was not on a secure connection, and it potentially exposed the data to anyone who had access to the network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the orthodontic practice had many patients and a large number of under-aged patients, the DPA decided to impose a hefty fine for not complying with the GDPR directive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have forms on your website on an insecure connection (HTTP), the transmitted data can potentially be tracked by hackers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This kind of data breach is difficult to detect, but you are still liable and need to report any data breaches in the next 72 hours as a company as per the GDPR directive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GDPR directive states that data processing must be handled in such a way as to ensure appropriate security, integrity, and confidentiality (e.g. by using encryption).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GDPR documents, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/recitals/no-83/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-32-gdpr/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, explicitly define the need for encryption, though no article expressly documents the usage of a TLS certificate on your website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, in theory, you don’t need it. In practice, though, it is strongly recommended as it conveys trust and keeps prying eyes away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;seo-and-google&quot;&gt;SEO and Google&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before GDPR, security and data breaches were on everybody’s radar, SEO improvements were the main benefit of having a secure website. Over the last ten years, Google made several efforts to push SSL certificates, and today it is the defacto standard for websites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-weak-ranking-signal&quot;&gt;A weak ranking signal&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier in 2014, Google already documented that HTTPS was a weak signal which could improve your position on the SERPs.&lt;br /&gt;https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2014/08/https-as-ranking-signal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having a TLS certificate does not mean your website automatically gets on the first page of Google. But if you are competing for a specific keyword, and your competitor’s website is not on HTTPS, it might just be the tiebreaker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-chrome-thinks-your-website-is-%E2%80%9Cnot-secure%E2%80%9D&quot;&gt;Google Chrome thinks your website is “not secure”&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/sitefig.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Schermafdruk-van-2022-01-26-16-33-03.png?resize=826%2C110&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Insecure website showing &amp;quot;Not secured&amp;quot; in the URL bar of the brwoser.&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;826&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In July 2018, Google Chrome started labelling websites lacking an SSL certificate as “not secure”. In addition to Chrome, other browsers have implemented similar notifications for sites without valid SSL certificates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, Google actively pushes websites to set up HTTPS. And since most if not all browsers are these days based on Chrome, it is the defacto standard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trust is still important for whether customers purchase goods online or not. Last year the UN reported that at least 30 % of users are &lt;a href=&quot;https://unctad.org/system/files/official-document/ser-rp-2021d15_en.pdf&quot;&gt;unwilling to buy online due to a lack of trust&lt;/a&gt;. So if your website is actively labelled as untrustworthy, it isn’t going to do you any good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;downsides&quot;&gt;Downsides?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did we mention that the cost of obtaining a certificate is free?&lt;br /&gt;If you’d like to win an argument with someone, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://doesmysiteneedhttps.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;https://doesmysiteneedhttps.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-set-up-https-for-your-website&quot;&gt;How to set up HTTPS for your website?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, the easiest way to enable HTTPS is to move your DNS to Cloudflare. Unfortunately, that does not mean the website is entirely secure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The webserver running the website still requires a TLS certificate to enable traffic between Cloudflare and your server to be encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare does provide certificates to fix that issue, but there are other options such as Let’s encrypt or Zerrossl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-check-for-potential-mistakes&quot;&gt;How to check for potential mistakes?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you have your website set up or migrated to HTTPS, it is easy to make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It might be that a redirect points to an HTTP URL, an incorrectly configured subdomain is still on HTTP, invalid canonical tags, or your SSL certificate is simply out of date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of mistakes that can happen, and it is easy to check for common SSL mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;check-for-http-pages-and-links&quot;&gt;Check for HTTP pages and links:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;with-google-operators&quot;&gt;With Google operators&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can make your search very specific. You can search for all pages on your website indexed by Google that use the HTTP protocol in the URL:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Asitefig.eu+inurl%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2F&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try it: “site:sitefig.eu inurl:http://”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/sitefig.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Schermafdruk-van-2022-01-26-20-44-17.png?resize=675%2C193&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Google operator serach&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;675&quot; height=&quot;193&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-free-account-with-sitefig&quot;&gt;A free account with Sitefig&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sitefig.eu/&quot;&gt;Sign up for a free Sitefig account&lt;/a&gt; and you’ll get access to all the broken links and resources on your website. Each page will be tested to ensure that it redirects to an HTTPS page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/sitefig.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image-1.png?resize=1024%2C304&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Broken link sscrenshot for sitefig&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What Is Web Governance and Why You Need It</title>
    <link href="https://sitefig.net/what-is-web-governance-and-why-you-need-it/"/>
    <updated>2022-10-08T07:33:34.000+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://sitefig.net/what-is-web-governance-and-why-you-need-it/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Web governance might seem like a relatively new term, but it has been around for quite some time now. As this is nothing tangible or calculative, most website owners or managers believe that it is either not being done or is simply not necessary. Both beliefs are wrong. For just about any website to succeed, individuals affiliated with it must understand what web governance is and why it is so crucial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is not fun, and yet it might be the primary factor behind your website sinking or sailing. Web governance refers to the processes and policies put in place to aid in the management and maintenance of the website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the time you are done reading this article, we believe you will have a firm grip on the many intricacies of web governance and the reasons behind its strong necessity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-web-governance&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Is Web Governance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand what web governance truly is, the first step is to know its many components. There is no particular set of methodologies that every website owner has to follow to govern their sites. Different people might feel the need to pursue different pathways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In general, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Website_governance&quot;&gt;web governance&lt;/a&gt; consists of processes, policies, and procedures. The key idea behind this is to establish a website regulatory process to set specific guidelines depending on the ideologies of the organization owning the website. If you already happen to own a business website and are constantly strategizing your digital marketing efforts, know that web governance is already in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, you might not be calling it that, but you already are involved in this. Some other names for web governance include digital governance or website management. Hence, you might as well start learning all about web governance so that you can streamline your business processes, even more, leading to increased productivity in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-most-common-components-of-a-website&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Are the Most Common Components of a Website?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every website is built on certain ideas, notions, constraints, and standards. The designer and the developer (at times both are represented by the same person known as a full-stack developer) take their time and make a comprehensive plan before going ahead and initiating the development. Make no mistake: a website not only requires a high quantity of quality content, but it also requires extensive work in the background, or away from the website altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The programmer takes care of the coding part and effectively builds the website from scratch. Ranging from the dynamic functionalities of the site to the various design and alignment aspects, the coder deals with them all and brings it down to a discernible structure. Yet this is not all. The code and the content are simply not enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A multitude of legal compliances must also be considered before expecting anything worth writing home about from the article. These compliances may include the overall accessibility of the website, the GDPR or general data protection regulation factor, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-publishes-the-website-and-when-is-it-done&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Publishes the Website and When Is It Done?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once all the data to be uploaded is prepared and accumulated, the hard part is over. Now it is up to the developer to integrate the information and data into the website. This depends on either the preference of the client for whom the site is being made or for the owner’s personal or commercial use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A point to remember here is that no significant set of skills is required for a website to be published on the web. A dedicated developer is not necessary, although having one can certainly be productive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Companies decide on the publishing time based on their deadlines or needs. Owners can delay as long as they want but should never rush when dealing with unfinished content. Doing this can be lethal for the website as any number of people visiting it might leave a strongly negative review. You will witness a drastic decrease in the traffic, and if the incompletions are still kept unattended, the traffic might eventually become non-existent. Timing is key and is a crucial aspect of website governance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-a-website-and-its-content-published&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Is a Website and Its Content Published?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let us begin with how a website and its contents are published onto the Internet. As mentioned above, there is no rule as to who will be carrying out the act itself but, in general, it is the developer who tends to load the website with the content. Every publisher requires three things to publish content on a website and eventually go on to upload the website itself onto the web: Internet connection, web development software, and a web server for hosting the site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among these, the web development tool is arguably the most important as this is where the site is created in the first place. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_Dreamweaver&quot;&gt;Dreamweaver&lt;/a&gt; is a great application for professional web designing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordPress&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is a world-renowned &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_management_system&quot;&gt;content management system&lt;/a&gt; or CMS, where developers can drag and drop any component they want and integrate them into the website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An Internet connection is required to carry out these tasks and go on to upload the freshly built website to a web server. Large-scale websites can use a single server on their own, while relatively smaller sites can take their places among other similar sites in shared servers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no cost associated with publishing content on a website, apart from perhaps the cost of the Internet. No physical materials are needed so money is saved on, say, paper and ink. On top of that, any content published on the web has a significantly higher chance of attracting more traffic (read visitors) than doing the same in the form of a book or journal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of the hundreds of thousands of people maintaining their websites every day. This in itself is a classic example of web governance. Thus, every company is doing web governance. The question is not if, but how good you are at it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-we-need-web-governance&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Do We Need Web Governance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a fair idea of what web governance is, let us take a look at why it is needed in the first place. One of the key reasons for web governance not getting the hype it deserves is down to the fact that most people have limited ideas on it. Even recurring implementers are often completely unaware of web governance despite using it every day. The following sections describe the primary motivations behind opting for web governance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;keeps-you-organized&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keeps You Organized&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake: Web governance is different from web management. The latter is the clear act of maintaining a website by sustaining its standards. However, the former is the implementation of a system following which the management is done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is more like a rule book where the rules are the acts of management. Having a clear set of guidelines for all your website managers will reduce inconsistencies significantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember, your website represents your brand. Any blemish on it will directly impact your business—something which can be avoided if a comprehensive plan is made and carried out. Anything ambiguous or misleading on your website will directly hamper the reputation and image of your brand, and of course, the site itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless a definite and precise web governance system is in place, you will need to face a lot of meetings and time-wasting quarrels just to get things in order. This reduces efficiency considerably.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting definitive standards, policies, and guidelines will enable the web development team to act without guessing. All independent web development aspects need to align at the very end. If not, know that something went wrong or was out of proportion during the development stage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a scenario where you have tasked your designer to create some lavish headers and footers for a page you will be publishing on your website. If the parameters and dimensions implemented by the designer do not match with the programmer who will be assembling all the content and uploading it, chances are, the entire work will fall apart. Having web governance methodologies integrated into the system, such mishaps hardly ever occur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;raises-the-efficiency&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raises the Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In simple terms, the more organized you get, the higher levels of efficiency you get to hit. Once you lay the foundations of web governance, it will help the website to evolve gradually over time. Think of a country or a province that has just achieved independence. The newly integrated laws take time to bring visible changes in the country, but will surely be discernible as time goes by. Web governance acts in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the fact that a plan is implemented, the right people get to work in the right departments. A programmer would not necessarily have to resort to writing content under such circumstances. Individuals can play to their strengths—raising efficiency in the process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every step being taken is done by the person best at it. There will always be someone at every end to deal with problems related to their departments. This high level of resource can only be done with efficiency if web governance is established on the website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, if all the departments and teams follow a specific plan, they can communicate with each other and develop the best version of their products. The sales and marketing teams can collaborate with the legal team and deal with any legal issues associated with the products, or the website itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IT professionals can get direct guidelines on how to design the products with the highest demand in the market. In short, all the teams can combine with ease and extract the best results as long as web governance is in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;understand-what-you-have&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand What You Have&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To establish a set of rules and guidelines for anything, you would need a comprehensive idea of what it truly is. Web governance acts in the same way. To integrate its methodologies into your website, you need to learn everything there is to know about the site. The best way to do that is to go for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audit&quot;&gt;audit&lt;/a&gt;, followed by constant monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many website owners resort to website audits when things start to go wrong. A website can stop yielding expected results even after keeping everything constant, and there can be plenty of reasons behind it. To figure that out, a web audit is required.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professional auditors like Sitefig start the process by thoroughly examining and scrutinizing all the characteristics and functionalities of the site. This is done to identify the key elements (or the lack thereof) that are contributing to its diminished performance levels. Auditing not only locates the issues but also how they can be resolved and avoided in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of the most common (and crucial) pieces of information that owners can gather after the completion of audits include where the errors are occurring, where the updates are required to be implemented, which links need repairing, where invalid data is hiding, spelling errors, and a whole lot more. Expert auditors spend a considerable amount of time monitoring the website to dig out all the inconsistencies and make reports accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These auditors also keep their eyes on compliance issues like GDPR, accessibility, and content. Unless GDPR is followed, not only does a website lose its claim to be considered a standard, but it also fails miserably in the battle of ranks against competitors. This causes a snowball effect and the website quickly loses its credibility among the visitors and sets on a path toward failure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is hampered massively, and even though you might have the most lightweight site out there, no one will be visiting. As for the content within, the higher the quality, the more traffic is generated. Auditors check the quality of the content as well and make their judgments based on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;build-standards-and-policies-using-web-governance&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build Standards and Policies Using Web Governance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only does the positive outcome of web governance take time to be visible, but the act of implementation itself also requires a handsome amount of time. Experts need to figure out important aspects like what cookies they have, their usage, the content available, the ease of access, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fundamental policies need to be applied to each website regardless of their types and applications. An example would be allowing traffic from every corner of the world. After that, specific policies are required to take the site to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For instance, a blogging site might have rules regarding underage content but a winery would have nothing like that. These policies should be extremely strict and should only be altered under dire circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These should also be very clear, straightforward, and logical so that developers and end-users do not find them perplexing or baffling. An example of a potential policy would be to mandate the use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Call_to_action_(marketing)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;calls to action&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on every page of the website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On top of all that, standards are established to guarantee that the quality, voice, and style of your website are consistent. There are several working hands on your website, and they may all have individual methods or ideas for accomplishing things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This pushes designers and copywriters to work towards a single goal, or standard in this regard. When there are a lot of individuals involved with your website, it can be challenging to keep standards up. The mix of policies and standards contributes to the success of your website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-regularly-and-keep-track-of-changes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Regularly and Keep Track of Changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you are well aware by now, web governance is a continuous process. It is not something that you focus on once a year during restructuring or cleanup. Make no mistake: we are not suggesting you bring changes to your active policies and standards. It is the governance aspects that need to be updated regularly, and the changes kept track of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let us take a real-life scenario as an example. Imagine a city going through troubled times due to increased crime rates. The local police get deployed. Does this mean the end of it? Certainly not. These individuals need to be monitored constantly and allocated based on the needs of specific locations. More soldiers might be required to dissolve the situation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specialized units might need to be deployed in darker regions during the night. All these are issues that require active control. Web governance is exactly that. Once you deploy your policies and standards, you need to keep monitoring the situation and make informed decisions throughout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Governance Protects Your Assets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A website is an asset, but that is not all. The associated brand image, goodwill, reputation, client base, etc., are all assets of your company. That is because none of these can be ignored without killing the business off completely. Web governance ensures that none of these is ignored by any means. Let us take a brief look at some of the benefits of web governance in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;brand-damage&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brand Damage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web governance negates the damage caused to the brand due to inefficient practices by the website managers. Having a set of rules and guidelines will not only keep the operations streamlined, but will also ensure that the clients do not take a negative view of the company. Large engineering organizations are heavily affected whenever their brand image is damaged. That is because clients tend to steer clear of companies that are not represented well on open markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any service that you take from, say, an engineer needs to be precise and spot on. Potential customers can only know about this from their brand image, thus making it extremely crucial to sustain high standards in this aspect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;legal-implications&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Union (EU) is ramping up on existing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt; cases, and rightfully so. Imagine an engineering organization that does not comply with GDPR guidelines. What are the chances of you going ahead and using their services? All you would know is the company does not keep your data safe, which is enough for the deal to fall through. Such is the importance of abiding by GDPR rules these days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;seo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The importance of SEO (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Search_engine_optimization&quot;&gt;search engine optimization&lt;/a&gt;) can never be overstated. For potential visitors and clients to access a website, it needs to be ranked high enough on the search engine results page (SERP). SEO ensures just that by improving anything and everything on the website and bringing them up to the standards of modern search engines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;accessibility-and-user-experience&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility and User Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent guidelines in popular search engines show that it is not just the components but also the overall user experience that plays a significant part in the ranking of the website. A user will tend not to spend time or return to a website if the experience was not something to write home about. Web governance efforts must focus on these factors for the website to reach the desired levels of excellence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;reduced-cost-and-time-to-deliver&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced Cost and Time to Deliver&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web governance is a system, not a particular task. If comprehensively followed, it not only reduces the overall costs but also contributes to faster deliveries. When each person working on the website follows a fixed set of guidelines, costs are reduced as no wrong decisions are made throughout. This, in turn, reduces the time of delivery as final outputs are obtained faster due to proper plans being followed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether you are aware or not, web governance is essential for the success of a website. You may not think you are following any guidelines, but in reality, you are, as shown earlier in this article. All you need to do is enhance those actions and convert them to hard and fast rules that all the website managers can abide by.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seek the help of professionals like Sitefig and determine the steps that you can take to establish complete web governance in your personal or business website.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PII Data Leaks: A Dangerous Situation</title>
    <link href="https://sitefig.net/pii-data-leaks-a-dangerous-situation/"/>
    <updated>2022-10-08T07:39:03.000+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://sitefig.net/pii-data-leaks-a-dangerous-situation/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Users/clients and organizations began to focus more on Personal Identifiable Information (PII) and, in general, personal data from 2010 onwards. Personal data controversies raised legal rights issues, ethical obligations, commercial disputes and information security concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021 wasn’t any different, with more data breaches than ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, more and more PII is being generated, transferred, and accumulated every day; and it becomes a target for hackers of all kinds. Yet, end-users often misjudge the threats, and some organizations believe that social engineering is merely a Hollywood plot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-what-is-pii&quot;&gt;But what is PII?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is formally defined (https://gdpr.eu/eu-gdpr-personal-data/) as “any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (‘data subject’); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s break that down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PII is information that organizations use on their own or combined with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person or identify that individual in context. Personal data comes in many different shapes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Names&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Addresses&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Financial information&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Login IDs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Biometric identifiers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Video footage&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Geographic location data&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Customer loyalty histories&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Social media&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;IP Addresses&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of the PII is publicly available and scattered across many websites, but do not underestimate the value of such information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hackers are not only interested in the amount of personal data found but are also interested in the correlation of these pieces. Public data breaches contain password hashes that can be decrypted using password dictionaries. With a bit of time and enough resources, a hacker can retrieve any password you use on your websites CMS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not many CMS systems enforce password requirements or regular password updates, which means your website can become a target quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of these attacks are never exposed because you gave the key to the house, and nobody saw any forced entry. As long as nothing changes, you might never know. That is why it is essential to be aware of any PII data on your websites and how it can be used against you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;pii-discovery-to-the-rescue&quot;&gt;PII Discovery to the rescue&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;International companies likely have many websites and limited resources. Manually verifying all those pages becomes a nightmare quickly, so best is that you use automated tools to scan your websites such as&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zaproxy/zaproxy&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;ZAP Proxy&lt;/a&gt;: the OWASP project has experimental support for PII to scan your website for leaks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cuit.columbia.edu/content/cuspider-pii-scanning-application&quot;&gt;CUSPIder&lt;/a&gt;: an open-source forensic file scanning application that can scan for PII related data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sitefig.eu/&quot;&gt;Sitefig&lt;/a&gt;: web-governance suite with an extensive set of PII scanners to make your website GDPR compliant.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-would-you-need-a-pii-scanner&quot;&gt;Why would you need a PII scanner?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your website is most likely updated right now. If you have a CMS, editors publish new content, and IT delivers updated solutions to suit your company’s needs. So a regular scan is required to maintain compliance and make sure you avoid embarrassing or costly mistakes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Save cost: it is better to prevent than to fix. If you can identify all the PII you have on your website on a regular basis, you can mitigate risk before they actually become an issue.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Customers trust: the worst UX a visitor can have is an email from your company about a data breach but if you do have to send it, make sure you do it within the legal restraints. Under GDPR regulations, your company must to report data breaches within 72 hours.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;GDPR regulations: to make sure your website adheres to the policy published on your website. Too often policies are published at the start of the project, and never updated. Keep your policies updated with facts so you can either edit the policy or update your website functionality and data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-won%E2%80%99t-happen-at-this-company&quot;&gt;It won’t happen at this company.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wishful thinking isn’t going to change the fact that hackers are hard at work. After servers become online, it takes minutes before hackers scan the IP address for vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Human error is a significant factor too, and it accounts for most of the vulnerabilities companies face. No matter how strict your policies are, you cannot rule out human error completely. Scanning regularly makes sure you don’t miss any issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-pii-discovery-part-of-the-regular-scan&quot;&gt;Make PII discovery part of the regular scan.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether you use open source tools or a free Sitefig account, any company with several websites should take care to scan for potentially damaging or necessary PII data. It is impossible to rule out publishing names and email addresses; telephone numbers and even bank account need to be published in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set up a regular scanning solution to keep your reputation intact and stay compliant.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
